Contact

ericaherreros@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ericaherreros-bsn-rn-ccrn-b25638a5 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

CPR Certified

Time Management Microsoft Excel

Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers

Critical Care Registered Nurse

Honors-Awards

HECHT Scholarship Recipient Hearts for Emma Scholar Kresge Scholarship

Erica Herreros BSN RN CCRN

Critical Care Registered Nurse at New York-Presbyterian Hospital Greater New York City Area

Summary

Erica Herreros is a Bilingual (Spanish/English) BSN-RN CCRN in the Pediatric Cardiac ICU at Morgan Stanley Children's Hospital of New York.

Erica is a member of the National Association of Hispanic Nurses with the New York Chapter. She was nominated and elected to be a board member of the nomination committee for two years (2017-2019). She will recruit and prepare a slate of candidates, under strict, confidential protocols to be elected for the scheduled election period.

Erica also serves as chairwoman for the communications/ social media committee for the National Association of Hispanic Nurses for the New York chapter. The Chapter website www.NAHNNY.org and electronic pages on the internet are maintained and updated in order to recruit and retain members.

Erica volunteered with Heart Care International on a mission trip to Chiapas, Mexico. Alongside Heart Care, Erica was able to provide high quality and compassionate nursing care pro-bono to indigent children with heart disease.

Erica was a Guest Lecturer at Hunter-Bellevue School of Nursing. She presented on Cardiac Conditions in the Pediatric Population and the Nursing considerations pertinent to taking care of this very vulnerable population.

Erica presented alongside Mr. Dan Suarez on Resume Writing and Interview Skills. Erica provided Nursing Students and Professional Nurses with many tips on how to successfully standout during an interview process.

Erica presented in the nurse specialities panel for the Nursing Students' Association of New York State 65th and 66th Annual

Conventions. She gave tips to nursing students on the importance of building your resume, interview skills and networking skills. She also shared her journey as a new graduate starting in the Pediatric Cardiac ICU.

Erica also presented in the 2016 annual NAHN Conference in Chicago, on the importance of leadership, mentorship and the power of the story.

Experience

New York-Presbyterian Hospital Registered Nurse August 2016 - Present (3 years 10 months) Morgan Stanley Children's Hospital of New York

Pediatric Cardiac ICU RN at New York Presbyterian Columbia/ Morgan Stanley Children's hospital of New York

NATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF HISPANIC NURSES

2 years 2 months

Member of the Nomination Committee

January 2017 - February 2019 (2 years 2 months)

Greater New York City Area

Recruit and prepare a slate of candidates, under strict, confidential protocols to be elected for the scheduled election period.

Obtain a statement of consent to serve and their qualifications for office. Facilitate throughout the election and installation process.

Social Media Manager January 2017 - February 2019 (2 years 2 months) Greater New York City Area

The Chapter website www.NAHNNY.org and electronic pages on the internet shall be maintained and updated in order to recruit and retain members.

Tacos Al Suadero

Waitress

January 2010 - August 2016 (6 years 8 months)

•Cited for excellence in interpersonal communications, teamwork, customer service, flexibility and reliability.

- •Demonstrated ability to interact with customers from diverse cultures and backgrounds
- •Waitressing allowed me to improve on my time management/prioritizing skills.

Sports and Arts in Schools Foundation 3 years 8 months

Counselor/Activities Director October 2011 - May 2015 (3 years 8 months)

- •Provided private instruction to individual or small groups of students to improve academic performance
- •Organized tutoring environment to promote productivity and learning
- •Assessed students' progress throughout tutoring sessions

Counselor

July 2012 - August 2014 (2 years 2 months)

- Assisted children from ages 5-14 in variety of sports activities
- Ensured that all children remained safe
- · Provided first aid assistance

Education

City University of New York-Hunter College

Bachelor of Science in Nursing (B.S.N), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse \cdot (2012 - 2016)

Forest Hills High School

Health Professions and Related Clinical Sciences, Other · (2008 - 2012)